<u>Jingkang Zhang</u>

zjk7773@gmail.com • +1 (510) 345-7475 151 Calderon Ave, Mountain View, CA 94041

github.com/JingkangZhang • linkedin.com/in/jingkang-zhang/ • jingkangzhang.com

Summary Statement

Hands-on fullstack Software Engineer with experiences in Web Applications, CRM Systems, and Internal Platforms. Consistent in delivering key business products and making technical contributions. Strong in problem solving and communication.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Python, CSS, SQL, NoSQL

Frameworks: React, Redux, Redux Saga, Koa.js

Tools: Git, GitHub, GitLab

Work Experience

TikTok Inc. May 2021-Present

Software Engineer Mountain View, CA

Full-stack developer on CRM system, an internal platform where operators view and manage TikTok content creators. Used daily by TikTok operations employees to perform their essential job functions and meet their work objectives. 1500+ DAU.

- Deliver key business projects, including a revamped TikTok Creator Verification Process, Creator Onboarding Journey, and various other features on the CRM platform. Work both on the FE and BE.
- Work as the tech owner / POC of 2 microservices; discuss requirements, answer inquiries, and lead development.
- Work on high priority confidential projects (compliance related): communicate extensively with legal, product, and operations stakeholders, navigate uncertain scenarios, and collectively make key decisions after weighing tradeoffs. Complete the technical portions of the projects under tight timelines.
- Perform oncall rotations, code reviews, technical reviews, and product reviews.
- Conduct interviews (about 3/week), co-mentor new joiners, onboard new members, onboard new oncall engineers, work together with the tech lead to grow the team from 2 to 8 engineers in 6 months.
- Technology: React, Redux Saga, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Node.js, Koa.js, SQL, MongoDB, Git.

Amazon June 2020-October 2020

Software Development Engineer Intern

Newark, NJ

Beijing, China

- Fullstack SDE intern on the Audible Financial Systems team. Created an internal event management console. Used extensively by Oncall Engineers and Business team to track their monthly work routines.
- Chat with support engineers, learn their needs, and transfer project knowledge to them.
- Technology: React, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Java, Node.js, DynamoDB, Git.

ByteDance May 2019-August 2019

Frontend Engineer Intern

- Frontend SWE intern on Toutiao team. Worked on CRM platform and user dashboard.
- Web-crawling and data-scraping with Node.js.
- **Technology**: React, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Node.js, Git.

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science, Minor in English Jun. 2018 – May 2021